LUIS GERARDO MARTÍNEZ VALDÉS

Hard worker, fast learner and achiever. Specialized in economic and financial analysis, with 5 years of experience in the IT sector; 3 years as an economic researcher, with particular interest in economic growth, investment banking, credit markets and financial development. I am looking for a role that can make a significant impact within the company, contribute to it, as well as expand my skills and knowledge.

CONTACT

luis.germartinez@gmail.com

+52(55)43475320

Porfirio Díaz 127, CDMX

Youtube Channel

@LMtzV

in Luis Martínez

SKILLS

Programming

Python R C++ STATA Java Script LaTeX

MATLAB/Octave



OS's

Linux MacOS Windows



Software & Digital Tools

Visualisation

(e.g. shiny app, dashboards)

Data handling/analysis Office



Languages

English
Spanish(Native Speaker)

German Portuguese



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2021-Actual

Sigma Latam Capital, CDMX

Investment Banking Specialist

Evaluation of investment projects, M&A, risk analysis and management, client & investor relations.

Neverland Consultants S.A. de C.V.
 Investment Banking and Venture Capital, Boutique Financial and Commercial Consulting

2018-2021

© CoreOne Information Technologies, CDMX Financial and Economic Analysis Valuation and financial/economic management of projects, analysis of prices and costs, financial efficiency, among others.

2019-Actual

Centro de Investigación Económica, ITAM,
 Junior Economic Researcher
 CDMX

Mainly focused on market structure(financial and credit markets), market efficiency, choice and game theory, applied microeconomics, economic growth and development

2018-2019

Centro de Investigación Económica, ITAM, Research Assisstant CDMX

2015-2018

♥ CoreOne Information Technologies, CDMX Finance Intern

Pricing and costing, Payroll Administration, Financial Statements Integration

EDUCATION

2014 - 2019

 Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de México, CDMX Economics

2016 - 2021

✔ Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de México, CDMX **Applied Mathematics**

2020 - Actual

▼ Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de México, CDMX Masters in Finance

GENERAL SKILLS

Data Analysis (R, STATA)

Teaching Experience Undergraduate Level

Project Managment

Fanancial & Strategic Planning

Risk Management

Technical Analysis

Investment Project Analysis

Firm Economics

Contract Evaluation

Firm Valuation

Venture Capital

M&A

TIME DISTRIBUTION

